前情提要
瑞秋 我知道你想追究到底
Rachel, I understand you have this drive to get to the very heart of things.
这值得赞赏
It's commendable.
有目击者吗
Eyewitnesses?
没有目击者 也没有受害者迹象
No eyewitnesses, no sign of the victim.
肖恩·埃默里 我要以涉嫌袭击 绑架
Shaun Emery, I'm arresting you on suspicion of assault,
-以及妨碍司法公正逮捕你 -什么
- kidnapping,and perverting the course of justice. - What?
知道死者是谁了吗
Do we know who the victim is?
汉娜·罗伯茨 人权问题专家
Hannah Roberts, human rights specialist.
主攻现代战争罪 恐怖主义
MoD war crimes, terrorism.
不对 她明明上了那辆公交车
That ain't right. She got on that bus.
肖恩·埃默里声称该证据不真实
Shaun Emery claims this evidence is somehow untrue.
不是这样的 这—切都没有发生
This ain't what happened! None of this happened!
但在反恐任务中我们工作的一部分就是
But here at counter-terrorism, accepting you can rarely see
接受你基本上看不到的全貌
the whole picture is part of the job.
接近目标 伊顿广场48号
Target approaching. 48 Eaton Square.
我们就位了 但没看到肖恩·埃默里
We're in position, and we do not have eyes on Shaun Emery.
我能看到他
I can see him.
我觉得有人在干扰我们的信号
I think someone's interfering with our feeds.
篡改证据
Tampering with evidence.
他们称之为「移花接木」
They call it correction
篡改那些不符合他们利益的事情
when they take something they don't like and they change it.
篡改效果100%逼真
100% photo-real manipulation.
你都不敢相信自己眼睛
You wouldn't believe your eyes.
他们要陷害他 你知道的
They're setting him up, you know that.
这是我第一次被派到这样的任务中
This is the first time I've been given a role in an op like this.
与你不同 我从没有过这种快速通道
I never had your fast-track privileges.
长官 我也不相信这些人
Ma'am, I don't trust these people one bit,
但肖恩·埃默里的视频不可能是假的
but Shaun Emery's video can't be fake.
我们尸体都找到了
We've got the body.
「移花接木」可以让情报变为证据
Correction turns intelligence into evidence,
把极端分子赶出街头
and keeps extremists off the street.
如果汉娜·罗伯茨不是肖恩杀的 那是谁杀的
If Shaun didn't kill Hannah Roberts, then who did?
长官 她在车上
Ma'am, she's there.
汉娜·罗伯茨
Hannah Roberts.
闭路监控被篡改过 但车上的录像没有
The CCTV was doctored, but not the footage from the bus.
你如果明白其中利害关系 就会走开
If you knew what was at stake, you would walk away
假装这一切从未发生
and pretend this never happened.
你能想象—旦「移花接木」被曝光 会造成多大影响吗
Can you imagine the impact if correction was fully exposed?
重要是你没破坏文件就好了
If you hadn't corrupted the file.
我相信你一定有副本
I'm sure you make copies.
这是我能想到的最好办法
I can't think of a better way to turn this problem
把这个问题变成机会
into an opportunity.
-为什么 -招募她
- For What? - Her recruitment.
加入我们 你将学会如何
If you join us, you'll learn how to use correction
用「移花接木」来做善事
as a force for good.
如果不加入呢
What if I don't?
我会像汉娜·罗伯茨—样被扔进后备箱吗
Do I end up in the boot of a car, like Hannah Roberts?
你是个警督
You're a Detective Inspector.
一定很聪明
Bright girl.
也许太聪明了
Too bright?
我什么时候入职
When can I start?
6个月后
啊 不错
Ah!  Nice, nice.
分开
Break.
很好 所以别等着对方进攻
Right. So, when he's about to attack, don't wait.
冲上去 先行动 主动出击控制局面
Go in, move first, you strike and take control.
好 我再看一下 开始
All right, let's see it. Go.
分开
Break!
好的 慢着点啊 天
All right, easy.  Whoa...
腹部 腹股沟 脚尖
Stomach, groin, top of the foot.
我每周都会讲解脆弱部位
We go through the points of vulnerability every week,
抓住脆弱部位可以制服对手
points that can be exploited to immobilise your opponent.
但是直接攻击气管
But a straight to the windpipe,
这不是自卫而是杀人
that's not self-defence. That's manslaughter.
只有生命受到危险 才可以攻击这些部位
You only need that kind of move if you believe your life is in danger.
备受关注的政府对赞达收购案的裁决
The Government's hotly anticipated verdict on Xanda's bid
要基于中国研究委员会的研究结果
rests on the findings of the China Research Committee.
但是中研委会有多公正呢
But just how impartial is the CRC?
我觉得你可以说 几个后排议员
I was thinking you could say, "A handful of backbenchers
掀不起什么大浪 连个小水花都翻不起来
isn't enough to cause a rift. It's barely enough to cause a ripple.
最后留白 让众人品味下
I think that works if you leave a gap, like you're reaching for it.
-就像我没有准备过一样 -正是
- What, like it's not prepared? - Exactly.
哦 伊丽莎进来了
Oh, here's Eliza.
你最好穿戴整齐 不然她会发飙的
Better cover up, or there'll be a tribunal.
-艾萨克 还有五分钟 –他知道
- Isaac, you've got five minutes. - Yeah.  He knows.
-他们测试过信号了吗 -和上次一样
- Have they tested the connection? - Yep, same connection as last time.
-爸爸 –怎么了
-Daddy.  -Yeah?
我们什么情况下能用到电 举五个例子
What are five ways we use electricity?
呃 电动汽车
Er, electric cars?
-家里的用电方式 -嗨 西蒙
- In the home. - Hi,Simone.
嗨 早上好伊丽莎
Oh, hi. Morning, Eliza.
可以玩电脑
You could have a computer.
爸爸得去玩电脑了
Daddy has to go on his computer.
还有电视 老爸要上电视了
Or TV. Daddy's going to be on TV...!
有什么跟你无关的例子吗
Anything not directly about you?
咖啡机
Coffee machine.
安全大臣艾萨克·特纳将在南部哈斯米尔的选区
Security Minister Isaac Turner is joining us live from
加入我门的直播连线 但在此之前
his constituency in Haslemere South. But before he does...
-BBC早间时刻 还有四分钟 -我会看的
- BBC Breakfast, four minutes. - Oh, I'll be watching...
才怪
..Sky.
-我们还没讨论关于中国的事务 -我还需要2个例子 老爸
- We haven't talked about China yet. - I need two more, Daddy.
你准备系哪条领带
Erm... Which tie are you wearing?
-我脖子上这条吧 -这领带有问题吗
- Probably the one around my neck. - What's wrong with the tie?
条纹缺乏MOTP的气质
Stripes. Not exactly MOTP.
-这领带没问题的 -我知道
- There's nothing wrong with the tie. - I know.
-MOTP是什么 -人民公仆
- MOTP? - Man of the people.
这是我美丽的老婆送给我的
This was actually a present from my very beautiful wife.
-说"人民公仆"不是更快吗 -爸爸
- I's quicker to say "man of the people."  - Daddy.
-我们能谈谈中国吗 -再给我两个例子 爸爸
- Look,can we talk about China,please? - I need two more,Daddy.
电话吧 西蒙妮
Ph-Phones? Simone!
-还有一个 -好了 去妈妈那里 好吗
- One more!All right,Harry. - Back to Mummy,OK?
回妈妈那里去
Back to Mummy.
这个问题引起了英国国会的分歧
It's the controversial question dividing Westminster -
中国的人工智能技术是否可以应用于机场
could Chinese AI technology be coming to an airport...
在看过赞达投售案之前 我必须对中国闭口不谈
And I can't say anything about China until I've seen the Xanda pitch.
同意 不管他们问什么 都要打官腔 保持中立
Agree. Whatever they ask, keep it safe, neutral.
最好把十字架塞进去
Probably best to go crucifix in.
怎么 我的信仰有问题吗
Oh. Rhys, is my faith a problem?
我可以完全放弃上帝
I mean, I could renounce God altogether,
-你觉得这样会让我的支持率更好看吗 –不需要
- if you think it might poll better? - No, no need.
7点40了 他们在等你
It's 7:40. They're waiting for you.
好的 给我一点时间做祷告
Yeah, I just need a moment to pray.
-好吧 -好的
- Right. - OK.
我开玩笑的啦 我下了
I'm kidding, for fuck's sake. Off you go.
我们可以信任这家中国科技巨头
But can the Chinese technology giant be trusted
让其对英国边境实施最先进的监控吗
to run state of the art surveillance at Britain's borders?
最适合回答这个问题的人就是
Who better to ask than the man in charge of the Government's
这份备受关注的中国研究报告的负责人 艾萨克·特纳
hotly anticipated China research report, Isaac Turner?
国务大臣 早上好
Minister, good morning.
早上好 威尔 劳伦
Yes, good morning, Will. Good morning, Lauren.
国务大臣 您一向号召团结一致 现在身处这场
Minister, as the man who called for unity, how does it feel to be
不断扩大的裂痕之中 是什么感受
at the centre of a growing rift?
劳伦 你是指这场关于面部识别的辩论
Er, I assume, Lauren, you mean the debate surrounding
这称不上是裂痕
facial recognition. It's hardly a rift.
30名议员指责中研委充斥着
30 MPs have accused the China Research Committee of being
中国怀疑论者
loaded with China sceptics.
作为安全大臣 我的职责是评估
Well, as Security Minister, it's my job to evaluate the risks
在英国边境安全事务中使用中国技术的风险
of using Chinese-owned technology in UK border security.
我可以向你保证 我们即将发布那份
And I can assure you, our forthcoming report on-on, er...
关于面部识别的合同
..the facial recognition, er, contract
将完全由
will-will be, er, solely in-informed by, er...
公正的专家
..unbiased, er, expert...
完全
Solely informed by, er...
该死
Shit...!
非常抱歉
I-I'm so sorry.
这个不折不挠的六岁小孩让我分心了
I'm being distracted by a very persistent six-year-old.
你好啊 小伙子
Hello, young man.
我天啊
Oh, my God.
我猜他应该不是中研委的一员吧
I take it he's not a member of the CRC?
不 除非这个缩写的意思是厚脸皮没礼貌
No. Not unless it stands for cheeky, rude something.
-我天啊 -早啊 哈里森
- Oh,my God. - Morning,Harrison.
你对监管中国技术有什么看法
What's your opinion on the regulation of Chinese technology?
-他们能看见我吗 -很多人都能看到你
- Can they see me? - A lot of people can see you.
而且你巧妙地回避了这个问题
And, brilliantly, you've avoided answering the question!
很是有政客的风范
A true politician in the making.
不 坦白讲 哈里森只是想找我
No. In fairness, I think Harrison just wants some help
-问家庭作业的事情 -好可爱
- with his homework. - Aw,adorable.
你在找一件家里需要用电的东西
You're looking for one more thing in the home that uses electricity.
那么
What about a...?
-相机  -相机
- Camera.  - Camera!
看起来您现在挺忙的 国务大臣
Well, it seems you have your hands full here, Minister.
家庭跟政府事务—样重要
No government matter takes priority over homework.
我想我们都认同这个价值观
I think that's a value we all share.
长官 早
Ma'am. Morning.
我... 很高兴遇到了你
I'm, er... I'm glad I caught you.
你不觉得这很奇怪吗
You know this is odd?
是很奇怪
I do.
你还在地图部门
You are still in mapping?
对 我正想跟你谈这个
Yes. That's what I wanted to speak to you about...
地图部门在六楼
Mapping is on six.
我知道
I'm aware.
7楼到了
Seventh floor.
我想问一下能否安排个时间来讨论
I wondered if we could schedule a time to discuss...
抱歉 我简报会要晚了
Excuse me. I'm due at a brief.
你迟早会上道的 警探
You'll find your way around eventually, Detective.
早啊
Morning, Nads.
-燕麦牛奶可塔多 你喜欢的那种 -真的吗
- Oat milk cortado,just how you like it. - Seriously?
不 加油站里弄来的 但还是热的
No. It's petrol station mud, but it's still warm.
受害者身份呢
Victim ID?
爱迪生·姚先生 中国人
A Mr Edison Yao. Chinese national, apparently.
今早被清洁工发现
Cleaner found him this morning.
有语言障碍 但我们已经请了翻译
There's a language barrier, but we've called for a translator.
-有自击者吗 -已经在每个门口安排了警员 挨个询问
- Eyewitnesses? - Got uniform on every door,asking the question.
闭路电视呢
CCTV?
正调取大楼内外的所有监控录像
We're pulling all footage from the building, inside and out.
进去吧
Shall we?
长官
Ma'am.
又让我叫你长官 又让我买咖啡哈
Can't do "ma'am" AND get the coffee.
我以为他就在我身边
I thought he was right next to me.
我只顾看电视来着 等等
I was too busy watching. Oh, wait.
是我妈妈 我再打给你
It's Mum. I'll call you back.
-你看到了吗 -所有人都看到了吧
- Did you see it? - I think everyone saw it.
-你出名了 哈里森 -我不出名
- You're famous, Harrison. - I'm not famous.
-你要上电视了-给你 亲爱的
- You're going to be on TV. - Here you go, darling.
我晚点打给你 我得走了
I'll call you later. I've got to go.
哈利 你刚才很可爱
Harry, that was very sweet.
但你要知道 爸爸工作时 你是不能进他办公室的
But you know you're not allowed in Daddy's office when he's working.
等爸爸当上首相讨论国家大事时
We won't be able to interrupt Daddy when he's Prime Minister
我们就不能打扰他了
talking about important things.
-看来我刚才说的是挺重要 -没错
- I think I WAS talking about important things. - You were.
你表现得出色 尤其是跟他―起时的样子
You were very good, especially with him.
看来我该多出出洋相
Maybe I should make a fool of myself more often.
能走了吗
Can you not?
那是狗仔队吗 还真有人在乎啊
Is that paps? Does anyone really care?
一枪毙命 受害者眼部中枪
Single gunshot fatality. Victim took one round to the eye,
脸上还有大量玻璃碎片
along with a shower of glass splinters to the face.
-眼部中枪 -尸体和伤口射入位置
- To the eye?  - The position of the body and location of the entry wound
说明枪击发生时 死者正站在门口
suggests the victim was standing by the door at the time of impact.
他正从猫眼中往外看
He was looking through the peephole.
子弹的口径值得玩味
It's the calibre of the round that interests me.
-继续说 -5.8毫米的
- Go on.  - 5.8mm.
比典型的9毫米口径小很多 这在英国非常罕见
A lot smaller than the typical 9mm and pretty rare in the UK.
武器有可能是一把92式QSZ自动步枪
In terms of weapon, you could be looking at a Type 92 QSZ automatic,
中国大陆以外通常找不到
but you don't normally find those outside mainland China.
验尸官初步推断死亡时间是晚上7点后
Coroner's first look puts time of death just after 7pm.
-关于这个姚先生我们还知道什么 -早上好 长官
- What else do we know about Mr Yao? - Morning, ma'am.
开始吧 翻译来了 也许能告诉我们更多
Here we go. Hopefully a lot more, now she's here.
早上好 是拉蒂警督吗
Good morning. DI Latif?
我是弗林警长 证人在这边
Yeah, I'm DS Flynn. This way for the witness.
她仍在震惊之中 但我们必须尽快从她身上
Obviously, she's had a bit of a shock, but we need the poor woman
问出一些被害人的情况
to throw some light on the murder victim, and pronto.
呃 好的
Er... OK.
你好
Hi.
这是针对性暗杀
This is targeted. Assassination.
也许是政治或国家行为
Maybe political or state actors.
怎么 你想去查吗
What, you want to kick it up?
我去叫反恐指挥部
I'll call SO15.
对不起
Erm... Sorry.
这位女士好像不会说英语
This lady doesn't seem to speak English.
嗯
Yeah.
我也不会说广东话
Well, I don't speak Cantonese.
你会说什么
Well, what do you speak?
英语
English.
还有从我祖母那里学的几句普通话
A few words of Mandarin from my grandmother.
你这算哪门子的翻译
What kind of translator are you?
抱歉我被困在塞尔赫斯特了
Apologies. I got stuck at Selhurst.
-再说一遍 -我听说你们需要一个会说广东话的人
- Come again? - I WAS told you needed A Cantonese speaker.
我可以为您服务
At your service.
-那么你是谁 -谭警员 长官
- So, who are you? - DC Tan, ma'am.
从今天开始 我应该是跟着您的
I'm supposed to start with you today.
我去
Oh, shit...
抱歉 我就
Sorry, I just, erm...
-长官 -怎么了
- Ma'am?  - What is it?
已经启动了住户安保系统
Got the resident's security system up and running.
-这系统很好 -好家伙
- It,quite the system. - Bloody hell.
我听说过家庭监控系统
I've heard of home surveillance,
但为什么要监控屋外的信号呢
but why monitor feeds outside the property?
他知道他需要小心
He knew he needed to watch out.
特纳先生 你对维多利亚·贝罗这个名字有印象吗
Mr Turner, does the name Victoria Bello mean anything to you?
来自拉各斯的维多利亚·贝罗
Victoria Bello from Lagos.
请退后 你们能退后点吗
Stay back, please. Can you stay back?
#哈里森家庭作业# 在英国排热搜第二
#HarrisonsHomework trending number two in the UK.
-第一是谁 -泰勒·斯威夫特
- Who,number one? - Taylor Swift.Taylor Swift.
我想我可以接受
I think I can live with that.
我能建议我们及时行乐吗
Can I suggest we, er, carpe diem?
把握当下
Seize the day.
我知道是什么意思
I know what it means.
-怎么做 -提前交付面部识别报告
- How?  - Deliver the facial rec report early,
提前发布公告
bring forward the announcement.
我们需要召集专家进行最后的投票
We'll need to assemble the experts for a final vote.
那就去吧 召集专家
Yeah, so do it. Gather the geeks.
听着 在我还没看过展示之前
Look, let's not imply I'm ready to vote
别暗示我准备好投票
before I've even seen the pitch.
-那 看后再说是吗 -对
- So, directly afterwards?  -Yep.
-很高兴见到你 -你好
- Hey. Nice to meet you. - How do you do?
-你好很高兴见到你 –你好吗
- Hi, Nice to meet you. - How are you?
他是香港来的 但他在伦敦一个亲人都没有
他来自香港 在伦敦没有家人
Er, he was from Hong Kong. He had no family in London.
她说他从不谈论自己
She says he never spoke about himself,
但她知道他是个科学家
but she knows he was a scientist.
这个我就不是很清楚了 好像是和电脑有关的
主攻电脑 她觉得是
Computer, she thinks.
她说他是个很注重隐私的人 很安静
She says he was a very private man, quiet.
抱歉打扰了
Sorry to interrupt.
我找到录像了
I found the recordings.
看起来不太高兴啊
Doesn't look too happy.
他说了什么
What's he saying?
我也想知道
That's what I'd like to know.
李夫人需要看这个吗
Does Mrs Li have to watch this?
这还不是最奇怪的地方
That's not the weirdest part.
那里没人
There's no-one there.
有鬼呀
她说了什么
What did she say?
鬼吗 你是说鬼佬吗
Gwai? As in gwai lo?
连我都知道那是什么意思 白人
Even I know that one - white man.
-你看到了一个白人 -不不不
- You saw A white man? -No,No,no.
在这种语境下 鬼并不是指白人
In this context, gwai doesn't mean white man.
这里头有鬼呀
她说那是鬼魂
She says it's a ghost.
存档所有录音
Archive all the recordings.
通知反恐指挥部
Call SO15.
将监控范围扩大到半径三英里内
Expand the CCTV trawl to a three-mile radius.
给我―份死者的资料
Get me a profile on the victim.
还有这个《黑衣女子》的签名证词
And a signed witness statement from the Woman In Black.
纳德斯
Nads...
长官
Ma'am.
很明显有人篡改了录像
Someone's obviously fucking with the footage.
你很清楚我们该打给谁
You know exactly who we need to call,
总之不是捉鬼敢死队
and it ain't Ghostbusters.
A111公路上已经覆盖了X光机
November X-ray 7118 is down on the A111.
A105上也安了祖鲁麦克9229
Ditto Zulu Mike 9229 on the A105.
有盲点吗
Blindspots?
印度湾3137在城市道路上给我们留下了0.17公里的盲区
India Golf 3137 has left us with a 0.17km compromise on the City Road.
这是个市政单位
It's a council unit,
所以应该会在从现在到2076年的任何时候修复完成
so we can expect repair any time between now and 2076.
派个工程师来修
Send an engineer to repair...
我们已经派了一名工程师去了
We've sent an engineer to repair the unit.
交接时有什么发现吗
Anything else from the handover?
B116公路上有盏灯在晚间熄灭了
A lamp went out overnight on the B116.
看起来不错 是的 修好其中一个
Looks good, yeah. Saving one of those...
- 一盏灯吗 -对的
- Er... Er,A lamp? - Correct.
搞一个24小时
Generate a 24 hour...
我们已经按照标准安排了一个24小时备用灯
We've generated a 24 hour beta feed as standard.
挺好
Good-oh.
我想知道他们什么时候会换掉
I'd like to know when they'll be replacing...
总督察凯莉
DCI Carey.
赞达面部识别系统
Xanda Facial Recognition.
这是世界上唯一一个能百分百准确
The only security system in the world to identify a human face
识别人脸的安全系统
with up to 100% accuracy.
将监控技术与人工智能相结合
Integrating surveillance technology with artificial intelligence,
赞达能为每一个被闭路电视捕捉到的个体生成3D模型
Xanda generates 3D modelling for every individual captured on CCTV,
即使这个人戴着口罩
even if the individual in question is wearing a face mask.
赞达的热像仪通过测量体温来标记可疑分子
Xanda's thermal cam measures body temperature to flag suspicious
可疑行为 或查明乘客是否携带病毒
behaviour, or to indicate if a passenger is carrying a virus.
赞达的数据库为世界各地的机场和城市地区
Providing digital surveillance for airports and urban areas
提供数字监控 其多样性丰富
across the world, Xanda's database is rich in diversity,
其人工智能也在不断发展
and its AI is ever evolving.
赞达致力于以同样的精度识别
Xanda is committed to recognising faces from every corner
来自全球各个角落的人脸
of the globe with equal precision.
我已经召集了中研委三点半来投票 内政部可以在7点后开会
I've called the CRC vote for 3:30. The Home Sec can meet after 7:00.
很高兴您能参加我们的展示 特纳先生
So glad you could attend our presentation, Mr Turner.
王磊先生 你们的成果真实太棒了
Oh, Mr Wanglei, that was very impressive.
赞达的执行董事会可不会每次推介
The Xanda executive board doesn't fly across the world
都穿越大半个地球
for every pitch.
我很想了解更多关于种族歧视的问题
I'm curious to hear more on the racial bias issue.
我们没有种族歧视的问题
We don't have a racial bias issue.
我们可以看你们的数据吗
Are we allowed to see your data?
一些面部识别系统错误识别黑人女性面孔的可能性
Some facial rec systems are ten times more likely
是错误识别白人男性面孔的十倍
to falsely ID a black female face than a white male one.
所以你知道我们很担忧
So, you see our concern.
赞达的人工智能不容易受到这些缺陷的影响
Xanda's AI is not susceptible to those failings.
但你不允许我们对程序进行独立测试
Yet you won't allow the programme to be independently tested.
特纳先生 有人告诉我您的中研委
Mr Turner, I was led to believe that your China Research Committee
是由专家组成的
was made up of experts.
里斯和伊丽莎不是委员会的成员
Oh, Rhys and Eliza are not part of the committee,
-我想你应该知道 -哦
- as I'm sure you're aware.  - Oh.
所以这些行踪不定的专家都在哪儿
So, where... are these elusive experts?
我们能见见他们吗
Might we ever meet them?
我们有责任保护他们的身份
We have a duty to protect their identities.
让我们在一个空房间里进行推介
Leaving us pitching to an empty room.
这不是空房间
It's not empty.
有我在
I'm here.
有时我觉得好像有 两个艾萨克·特纳
Sometimes it seems to me as if there are...two Isaac Turners.
在电视上 你说你思想开放
On television, you say you have an open mind,
但事实上 我觉得你早就做了决定
but in reality, I get the sense your decision has long been made.
我该相信哪个艾萨克·特纳
So, which Isaac Turner should I believe?
王磊先生我认为你
I have to assume there's a chance, Mr Wanglei,
有可能在录音
that you're recording this.
所以 为了方便你们的监听设备
So, for the benefit of whatever listening device you may
我想私下里说 这是我
have running, what I'm about to say is my own opinion,
个人的观点
off the record,
并不能反映英国政府的观点
and doesn't reflect the views of the British government.
我不需要展演就知道你们是世界领袖
I don't need a presentation to know you're the world leaders.
没有人能搞得出中国那样的监控
Nobody spies like China.
也许你把我们却中国当局搞混了
And perhaps you're confusing us with the Chinese authorities.
你们是一体的
You're one and the same.
别担心我不怪你 你又没得选
Don't worry, I don't blame you. It's not like you have a choice.
怎么说的来看
What is it?
私营企业必须与国家情报部门合作
The private sector must collaborate with national intelligence.
这是中国的法律
It's Chinese law.
所以当北京方面打电话让你
So, when Beijing calls and asks you to look the other way while
在他们的间谍溜过机场安检时睁一只眼闭一只眼
their spies slip through airport security, or orders you to
或者命令你识别出中国在英国地盘上的政敌
facially recognise China's political enemies on British turf...
你会说什么
..what are you going to say?
拒绝吗
No?
中国人工智能技术的使用不会对你的安全
The use of Chinese AI technology poses no threat to your safety,
人身安全或你的生活方式构成威胁
your security, or your way of life.
嗯 我读过宣传稿的
Yeah, I read the propaganda.
对不起 是新闻稿
Sorry, press release.
甚至我的政府里也会有人天真到相信这些
There may even be ministers in my government naive enough to believe it.
不幸的是 如果没有我的推荐
Unfortunately for you, without my recommendation,
你们的竞标到不了他们手里
your bid will never reach them.
只要我还是安全大臣
As long as I'm Security Minister,
英国边境就不会被中华人民共和国的
Britain's borders won't be monitored by a storefront
门面公司监控
for the People's Republic of China.
看来我们是在浪费时间
It seems we've wasted our time.
如果我们真像你说的那样擅长监控
If we're as good at spying as you say we are...
你应该再小心点
..you might be a little more careful.
我没什么好隐瞒的
I've got nothing to hide.
每个人都有东西可隐瞒
Everybody has something.
谭警员对吧
Erm... DC Tan?
克洛伊
Chloe.
我
Yeah, I'm...
抱歉 他们说翻译她在路上了 所以我以为
Sorry about earlier. They said the translator was on HER way, so I...
我是中文翻译
I was the Chinese translator.
我这样是不是挺没礼貌的
Is that terrible? That's terrible, isn't it?
我不会举报你的
I'm not going to report you.
甜甜圈我请
The doughnuts are on me.
所以你现在要贿赂我闭嘴了吗
So, now you're buying my silence?
什么
What?
纳迪亚
Nadia.
恭喜你升职了
Congrats on the step up.
同喜
Likewise.
禁地之内的工作怎么样
How's the inner sanctum?
挺忙
Busy.
受害者是谁
So, who's your victim?
中国人 在他的公寓里被暗杀
Chinese national. Assassinated in his apartment.
你需要跟中国大使馆接治
You'll need access to the Chinese embassy,
向高级调查官简介情况
SIO support to brief the service.
他是持不同政见者吗
Was he a dissident?
我不是在问你怎么办这个案子 瑞秋
I-I'm not asking you how to run the case, Rachel.
这案子里有别的东西
There's something else.
他在公寓里里外外都装了监控
He had CCTV all over the flat, inside and out.
只是不见枪手
Only, the shooters are nowhere to be seen.
有人篡改了监控
Someone's doctored the CCTV.
否则我们要找的就是一个恶作剧鬼魂
That, or we're looking for a poltergeist.
所以你才打电话给我
That's why you called me.
我想你可能会有一些 见解
I thought you might have some...insight.
我为什么会有呢
Why would I?
哦 我明白了
Oh, I see.
我们需要什么神圣的暗语吗 或者特殊形式的握手
Do we need a sacred code, or something? Special handshake?
如果你想让我看看监控 请直接发给我
If you want me to take a look at the footage, send me the...
不可能 这是我们的地盘 不是你们的
No way. It's on our turf, and not SO.
怎么 你觉得我们的信任你们吗
Oh, what, you expect our trust?
我们还是别管了 帕特里克 我们手头的事儿已经够多了
You know what, let's just leave it, Patrick. We've got enough going on.
提醒我一下 肖恩·埃默里到底判了多久
Remind me. How long did Shaun Emery get in the end?
4年 是吗
Four, wasn't it?
6年
Six.
一个无辜的人坐了六年牢
Six years for an innocent bloke.
我帮不了你们 抱歉
I can't do this. I'm sorry.
不 我明白
No, I get it.
打不过就加入 是吧
Can't beat them, join them, right?
下午好 尊敬的
Good afternoon, distinguished members
中国研究委员会成员们
of the China Research Committee.
还有格雷戈里
And Gregory.
我需要提前提交这份报告
I need to deliver this report ahead of schedule,
所以问题是 什么时候能完成
so the question is, how soon can that happen?
我真心希望答案是 今天完成 艾萨克
I really hope the answer is, "Today, Isaac."
今天完成 艾萨克
Today, Isaac.
嘿 谁不想多要点时间呢 对吧
Hey, one always wants more time, right?
但是多亏了你们宝贵的贡献
But thanks to everybody's invaluable contributions,
还有最后一刻的加工
and with some last-minute polishing,
我有信心今天就发布
I'm confident we can publish today.
除非有人极力反对
Unless anyone has any dazzling objections?
最终投票的人不全啊
Not everybody is present for the final vote.
爱迪生呢
Where is Edison?
好吧 没有他我们也继续吧
Right, well, I think we go ahead, regardless.
我们又不是不知道他对中国的立场
It's not like we don't know his position on China.
抱歉打扰了 大臣
Sorry to disturb, Minister.
你得看一下邮件
You need to check your inbox.
跟成干上万的签证申请者—样 维多利亚·贝洛梦想着
Like thousands of visa applicants, Victoria Bello dreams
能在英国生活和工作 但这项申请十分特别
of living and working in the UK, but hers is no ordinary application.
这位驻拉各斯的护理人员声称
The Lagos-based care worker claims her three-year-old son's father
她三岁的儿子的父亲是英国安全部长艾萨克·特纳
is Britain's Security Minister, Isaac Turner.
-这是哪家媒体 –新闻怪胎 一些非主流网站
- Who,is this? - News Freak. just some fringe site.fringe site.
可看上去这页面搞得很像《华盛顿邮报》
Makes Buzzfeed look like The Washington Post.
告他们 然后让他们撤销
Sue the living shit out of them.
还没上线 只是先发给我们要个建议
It's not online. They've just sent it to us for comment.
好吧 那我就给他们点建议
OK. Er, here's my comment -
如果你敢公开 我们就公告你个底儿掉
if you publish, we'll sue the living shit out of you.
好吧 那么大臣全面否认
OK. So, the Minister strenuously denies...
不 这根本不需要否认
No, it's not worthy of denial.
-我们不会对个人私生活发表意见 –等等 这个
- We don't comment on personal matters.  - Wait, this...
这是他们干的 赞达
This is them, this is Xanda.
看看这个网站是谁搞出来的
Find out who owns this site.
我敢说位置一定在加州 但出资人是北京的
Guaranteed, they'll be based in California, funded by Beijing.
-走吧 伊丽莎 -去哪
- OK. Come on,Eliza. - Where are we going?
让王磊看看我们可不怕这一套
To show Wanglei we're not afraid.
干得好
Nice work.
特纳先生
Mr Turner.
我现在没时间
I'm on rather a tight schedule.
你还要忙着继续中伤别人是吗
You got more people to defame?  Oh.
鉴于我们之前谈话的结果 我的同事
In light of our previous conversation, my colleagues
已经决定返回北京了
have decided to return to Beijing.
我得送他们去机场
I must escort them to the airport.
你这算... 算什么 恐吓吗
What-what is this, intimidation, or...?
你不知道我在说什么是吗
Oh, you don't know what I'm talking about?
他认为这是我们干的
你可以随便制造假新闻
You can fake as much news as you want,
但如果你认为自己可以干预英国政府的政策
but if you think you can meddle in UK government policy,
那你可就大错特错了
you're sorely mistaken.
如果我们真想干预 特纳先生
If we wanted to meddle, Mr Turner,
你觉得我们就这点本事吗
do you think this is the best we can do?
失陪了
Excuse me.
长官 我打过电话 发过邮件
Ma'am. I tried to call, and email.
-那你现在是在跟踪我咯 –我查到了点东西
- I'll start to think you're stalking me.  - I've got something.
是重案组在处理的 针对性谋杀
It's with homicide, a targeted killing.
监控有些不对劲
The CCTV threw up some...concerns.
属于我们工作范畴的那种
Our kind of concerns.
我不知道这跟我们的行动有没有关系 但是
I don't know if it crosses any of our ops, but...
把监控拿来吧 我会找人看看
Pass on the details. I'll assign someone to take a look.
长官我想亲自参与
Ma'am, I was hoping I could take a look.
你需要7楼的批准才行
You'd need clearance for the seventh floor.
我知道 所以我才
I realise that. This is what I...
另外 你在地图部 你走了谁负责呢
Besides, you're in mapping. Who'd run mapping?
地图部自己能搞定
Mapping runs itself.
别太谦虚了
Don't be modest.
地图部需要你这样尽职尽责的人才
The department needs someone with your diligence.
这可是荣誉奖章
It's a badge of honour, you know.
爱迪生·姚傍晚6:55分回到家
Edison Yao returns home at 6:55pm.
接下来直到33分钟后才又有人出现
The next event isn't until 33 minutes later,
是一个送货司机于7:28分进入大厦
when a delivery driver enters the building at 7:28pm.
那是袭击发生的28分钟后了
28 minutes after the attack.
我们从各个角度都查过了 在受害人进入大厦
We've trawled every angle. No-one enters the building
和袭击发生之间没有人进入大厦
between the victim's arrival and time of attack.
扩大时间范围
Expand the timeframe.
继续找
Keep looking.
如果袭击者能在爱迪生·姚的监控上抹掉自己的痕迹
If the shooters can scrub themselves out on Edison Yao's camera,
那他们也—样能黑进大厦监控
they can hack street CCTV.
这事我们不能再隐瞒反恐部了
We can't keep this from SO15 any longer.
你得把自己的自尊放在一边 让他们掌握主动权
You're going to have to swallow your pride and give them primacy.
自尊
Pride?
只要他们一插手 这案了就变成他们的了
As soon as they get their claws into this, it'll be their case, not ours.
如果我们不能信任瑞秋·凯莉 那还有谁
And if we can't trust Rachel Carey, then who?
你的另一个朋友 那个密探吗
Your other friend, the spook?
你非得哪壶不开提哪壶是吗
Not going to let me forget it, are you?
怎么 故意对篡改证据视而不见
What, turning a blind eye to evidence tampering,
然后好升职吗
and then taking a promotion?
受害人资料 长官
Victim profile, ma'am.
他的记录只有从2017年开始的 那是他刚进入英国的时间
His records only go back as far as 2017, when he entered the UK.
在那之前都是空白的
Before that, it's a blank.
估计爱迪生·姚也是个新身份
I'm guessing Edison Yao is a new identity.
他有可能是
He may have been a...
中国的政治流亡者 我知道
Chinese dissident. Yes, I know.
电活下载记录显示 最后一次尝试拨打电话是在傍晚6:59分
Phone downloads says last activity was an attempted call at 6:59pm.
正好在袭击发生的时候
Bang on the time of attack.
也许他试图警告某人吧
Maybe he was trying to warn someone.
打给谁的
Caller ID?
电话簿上显示是诺克斯 打通了
Saved on the phone as "Knox". It's ringing out.
格雷戈里·诺克斯 他好像是个数据分析师
Gregory Knox. He's some kind of data analyst.
办公室在伦敦中心一区
Office in EC1.
我来查
I'm on it.
她让我在地图部工作
She's got me in mapping.
我已经升为总督察了 可她却只给了我一个换电灯泡的职务
I've been promoted to DCI. She's got me on a fucking light bulb duty.
这是流程中至关重要的一个部门
It's a crucial part of the process.
如果7楼没有最新的全面的监控地图
If seventh floor don't have an up-to-date comprehensive picture
他们就什么都做不了了
of the CCTV map, they can't do their jobs.
但加兰德之所以让我在那是因为她不信任我
But Garland's keeping me there because she doesn't trust me.
还是不信任
Still.
不信任别人是他们的常态啊
Not trusting people is sort of their stock in trade.
是我主动要求加入的
Look, I signed up to be part of this.
利用「移花接木」技术来执行任务 为了跟精英中的精英—起共事
To run ops using correction. To work with the best of the best.
我应该参与的项自都没有得到许可
I haven't even got clearance to the programme I'm supposed to be
这样是不对的
working on. It's not right.
-听我说 瑞秋 我们应该 -抱歉 我只是
- Look, Rachel, we should move... - Sorry, I just...
我也没有别人可以倾诉了
Who else can I speak to?
你最近睡得好吗
How are you sleeping?
跟以前一样 怎么了
No worse than usual. Why?
在俄国 有句老话
You know what they say in Russia...
你知道的越少 睡得就越好
..the less you know, the better you sleep.
那你岂不是整晚都不能睡了
You must be up all night.
我来找格雷戈里·诺克斯
I'm looking for Gregory Knox.
哪家公司的
Which company?
凶杀和重案组的
Homicide and serious crime.
我是说 他是哪家公司的
I meant, which company is he from?
特鲁罗数据分析
Er, Truro Analytics.
特鲁罗在10层 但他们应该都下班了
Truro's on the tenth, but I think they all left.
能给他打个电话吗
Can you give him a call?
我得交班了 抱歉
I need to hand over. Sorry.
他还没刷卡 所以应该还在楼里
Er, he hasn't swiped out, so he's still in the building.
-10楼是吧 -对 但你需要通行卡
- Tenth floor, you say? - Yeah, but you need a pass.
警察调查还用通行卡吗
What, for an urgent police matter?
是的 我需要问一下经理 但他们都下班了
Yeah. I'd ask my managers, but they've all gone home.
行吧 那就不用你操心了
Yeah, don't worry yourself.
看来警察靠警徽就能随便进入的年代过去了
Time's gone by a police badge would've got you somewhere.
你要调查什么吗
You're conducting an investigation?
只是想找个人
Just trying to find a bloke.
特鲁罗的格雷戈里·诺克斯
Gregory Knox, Truro.
如果他不在办公桌旁 可以去睡眠舱看看
If the gentleman is not at his desk, try the sleeping pods.
睡眠舱
Sleeping pods?
11楼 到了你就知道了
Level 11. You will see.
睡眠舱
Sleeping pods...
你好 欢迎参加智力测试 提问还是放弃
Hello, and welcome to Quiz, Question or Quit -
测试会让你陷入两难境地
the quiz show that puts you in a quandary.
请回答 你在哪
Do you quiz, where you...
提问 您选择向另―位参赛者提出自己的问题
Question, where you opt to fire one of your own questions
还是放弃
at another contestant. Or quit...
如果7楼没有最新的全面的监控地图
If seventh floor don't have an up-to-date comprehensive picture
他们就什么都做不了了
of the CCTV map, they can't do their jobs.
你还在地图部吗
You are still in mapping?
是的 我正想跟你说这个呢
Yes. That's what I wanted to speak to you about.
我认为我们应该告诉他们
I think we tell them either it's going to happen or it's not.
我们没有时间 扎克
We don't really have the... Zac!
轰动人物啊
The viral sensation.
#哈里森的作业#
#HarrisonsHomework.
-给你做宣传的是谁 -莱斯·爱德华 但这不是他的作品
- Who's your SpAd? - Rhys Edwards. But it wasn't his.
这家伙嫉妒了
This one's jealous.
甚至建议我设计一段好笑的家庭视频
Even suggested I stage a hilarious family video.
可孩子们到了上大学的年龄就不爱拍了 麦肯齐
Doesn't work when the kids are college age, McKenzie.
不是 不是特意安排的
It wasn't... It wasn't staged.
詹姆斯
James.
不用了 我不喝 待会就走
Oh. No, nothing for me. I can't stay.
还要上电视吗
More television appearances?
内政大臣 我正想跟你谈一下这个
Home Secretary, that's actually what I wanted to catch you about.
我要提前提交中研委的报告了
I'm delivering the CRC report early.
放了一份副本在你桌上
So, there's a copy sitting on your desk,
但如果你想回家提前看的话
but just in case you fancy a little fireside reading.
让我猜猜
Let me guess.
作为一家中国公司 赞达面部识别公司受法律约束
As a Chinese-owned company, Xanda Facial Rec are bound by law
要在国土安全问题上协助北京
to assist Beijing in matters of national security.
另外 他们缺乏透明度 让我们很不放心
Furthermore, their lack of transparency does nothing
不知道他们的人工智能是否已通过针对种族歧视的测试
to reassure us their AI has been tested against racial bias.
总之 我们发现很难支持
In conclusion, we find diddly squat to support the claim
赞达面部识别公司对我们的安全
that Xanda Facial Rec poses no threat to our safety,
安保和生活方式不构成威胁的说法
our security, or our way of life.
看来我根本不需要专家委员会
Then it seems I didn't need a committee of experts.
-只要来这喝―杯就都搞定了 -别胡扯了
- I could have just Come here for A drink. - Nonsense.
我们最擅长的就是成立个委员会
Setting up committees to determine things we already know
来决定我们已经知道的事情
is what we do best.
所以 我想首相应该会接受我的建议
So, I trust the PM will take my recommendation
重新找一家面部识别供应商
and find an alternative facial rec provider?
如果不接受才傻呢
Well, he'd be a fool not to.
哦 话说早了
Oh, wait.
我打算今晚宣布
OK, well, I'd like to announce this evening.
-在晚间新闻有个时间段 -这么着急干嘛
- There's a slot on Newsnight. - Why the rush?
赞达 也不算是威胁吧
Er, Xanda are being... not intimidating, but...
其实是威胁
Intimidating?
我说不算是威胁
I said NOT intimidating.
-你没事吧 -有什么事需要我知道的吗
- Is everything all right,mate? - Anything I should know about?
没有 就是我
No, nothing. It's just, I...
我觉得越早宣布越好 这样才能让大家重视起来
I feel the sooner we announce, the stronger message we send.
好吧
All right.
计划不错 执行吧
Good plan. Make it happen.
除非媒体有其他想法
Oh, unless comms has a problem with it.
我提醒晚间新闻一下
I'll give Newsnight a ring.
我的人可以打给英国广播公司
My team can call the BBC.
你忘了 麦肯齐这方面很厉害的
You're forgetting, McKenzie, Zac's a top booking.
-那我走了 -再见
- Home Secretary.  - Zac.
紧急呼叫 斯宾塞广场 特鲁罗数据分析公司
Urgent assistance. Truro Analytics, Spencer Square.
需要未通知的恐怖分子紧急响应
I need a PLATO response.
有人开枪 重复 有人开枪
Shots fired. Repeat, shots fired.
格雷戈尔·诺克斯
Gregory Knox?
弗林警长 重案组的
DS Flynn, homicide.
大厦里有持枪闯入者
There are armed intruders in the building.
我需要你跟我走 速度 别出声
I need you to follow me, quickly and quietly.
什么意思
Well, what do you mean?
马上
Now!
什么鬼 是恐怖分子吗
What the hell is it? Is it... Is it a terrorist?
你了解这座大厦吗
How well do you know this building?
我 我刚来上班没多久
I-I... I just come here to work.
看来你工作还挺努力的
Looked like you were hard at it.
底下有防火门吗
Is there a fire door at the bottom of this?
我想应 应该有吧
I-I...I think so.
走
Let's go.
–现在怎么办 –继续走
- What now? - Just keep moving.
要不要躲起来
Shall we try to hide?
没意义了
No point.
他们知道我们在哪
They know exactly where we are.
他妈的监控
Fucking stupid CCTV...!
现在可以躲了
Now we can hide.
开门 找个能打开的门
Pick a door. Any door that opens.
-他们会找到我们的 –胡说
- They,going to find us... - Bollocks.
武装部队随时会到
Armed unit should be here any second.
等他们一听到警笛
Soon as they hear the blues and twos,
他们会吓得屁滚尿流
they'll them shit themselves and run.
来 进去
Here. Get in.
凯莉
Carey.
-内政大臣和通讯部全力支持 –太好了
- Full support from the Home Secretary and comms. - Excellent.
-现在就让我上晚间新闻吧 -我让BBC来接你
- Now, put me on Newsnight. - I'll get the BBC to send transport.
其实 我一个半小时后就能回家了
Actually, you know what, I can be home in an hour and a half.
-我在那里接受采访 -当然 著名的居家工作嘛
- I'll do it from there.  - Oh, of course, the famous home studio.
艾萨克·特纳
Isaac Turner?
诺克斯先生是中国研究委员会的二号人物
Mr Knox was the second target from the CRC.
-所有成员可能都有危险 –那我的家人呢
- All members may be at risk. - Well, what about my family?
我们已经派了安保人员到你家
We've sent protection officers directly to your home address.
嫌疑人是谁
And who are the suspects?
我们会在去安全屋的路上给你详细说明
We'll give you a full briefing en route to the safe house.
纳迪亚 纳迪亚
Nadia! Nadia.
他们正在给他做手术
They're operating on him.
他现在肺萎缩 还有一处胸部伤口 情况危急
He's got a collapsed lung and a second chest wound, critical.
为什么他一人行动
Why was he alone?
去你的 他去执行常规调查
Fuck you. It was a routine inquiry.
如果你这么在乎 我们来找你的时候你就会帮忙了
And if you cared so much, you could have helped when we asked you.
这事已经失控了
This has gotten way out of hand.
我让反恐指挥部去查这个案子 我们会抓到做这件事的人渣
Let me run the case out of SO15. We'll get the scum who did this...
没必要 我已经打过电话了
That's not necessary. I've already made the call.
你需要一个更高级别的调查官
You need a higher ranking SIO.
警探督察长够了吗
Will detective superintendent suffice?
长官
Ma'am.
谢谢你们让我注意到这个
Thank you for bringing this to my attention, both of you,
你俩还方法不同 证人呢
in your own different ways. The witness?
诺克斯先生在等待室
Mr Knox is in the waiting room.
受了惊 但他正在恢复
In shock, but he's recovering.
我是谭警员 长官
DC Tan, ma'am.
很高兴见到你
Pleased to meet you.
他说他没看到嫌犯的样子
He said he can't get a visual on the suspects,
他们在武装部队到来之前就走了
and they were gone before the ARVs arrived.
他说听起来像是两个袭击者 也许更多
He said it sounded like two assailants, maybe more.
没有目击者 监控录像里的嫌疑人已经被清除了
No eyewitnesses. The suspects have been scrubbed from the CCTV,
-就像爱迪森·姚—样 –帕特里克一定看到了
- just like with Edison Yao. - Patrick must have seen them.
近距离射击胸部 你会看得很清楚的
Chest shot at close range, you would have got a good look.
等他恢复好 弗林警长会给我们做笔录的
And when he is able, DS Flynn will give us a statement.
让他当证人 他需要保护
Makes him a witness. He'll need protection.
你去告诉我们他接下来需要去看医生
You'll be telling us he needs to see a doctor next.
委员会那边的情况如何
What's the status with the committee?
在按计划行事 长官 所有成员都在转移中
As instructed, ma'am, we've got all members in transit,
包括艾萨克·特纳
including Isaac Turner.
-事态已经得到控制了 –艾萨克·特纳议员吗
- Contained and controlled. Isaac Turner, the MP?
瑞秋 拜托
Er, Rachel. Please.
拉蒂夫警督 跟我来
DI Latif, with me.
他的情况仍然很危急
He's still in a critical condition,
但你应该很快就能去见他了
but you should be able to go and see him soon.
你叫伊冯 对吧
It's Yvonne, isn't it?
我是瑞秋 我
I'm Rachel. I...
我跟帕特里克在凶案组一起办过大案子 所以我
I ran a big case with Patrick in homicide, so I...
我知道他是个好人
I know what a bloody good bloke he is.
我不想太唐突 我
I don't want to intrude. I just, erm...
如果有什么我能做的
If there's anything I can do.
你可以去抓凶手
You can get the bastard who did it.
一定是他们
Yes, it must be them.
他们终于害了爱迪生 那个可怜人
They finally got to Edison, the poor bastard,
现在他们又盯上了格雷戈里
and now they've gone after Gregory.
是的 我告诉过这些警探
Yeah, I told these detectives
他们应该找的是谁
exactly who they should be looking for.
诺克斯先生
Mr Knox.
安保小组来了 他们会把你转移到安全的地方
The protection unit are here to transfer you to a safe location.
他 他怎么样了 是他保护了我
How...how is he? He protected me.
他 他救了我的命
He...he saved my life.
亲爱的 我们该走了
Sweetie, we're going to go.
来吧 宝贝
Come on, babe.
艾萨克
Isaac?
别担心我 伊丽莎 我有自己的武装民兵
Yeah, don't worry about me, Eliza. I've got my own armed militia.
艾萨克·特纳吗 我是侦缉警司杰玛·加兰德 反恐指挥部的
Isaac Turner? I'm DSU Gemma Garland, SO15.
是的 我在打电话
Yes, I'm on the phone.
请稍等
One second.
打电话给里斯 告诉他我们要远程直播《晚间新闻》
Call Rhys and tell him we're doing Newsnight remotely.
-好的 -好 待会儿见
- Right,OK. Yeah? - Yeah. Speak later.
抱歉打扰了 这事关你的人身安全
Sorry to disturb, Minister. It's just a matter of your
我得请你把手机关掉
personal safety. I must ask you to turn off your phone.
是的我需要一台配有像样摄像头的笔记本电脑
Yes, I'm going to need a laptop with a decent webcam,
需要是近三年的产品
something built in the last three years,
而且要有个能让我坐下接受采访的地方
and somewhere I can sit and give an interview.
恐怕这是不可能的
I'm afraid that's out of the question.
帕特里克
Patrick.
你他妈最好能醒过来
You better fucking wake up.
我们需要你
We need you.
我需要你
I need you.
不 我没加入他们 你个大白痴
No, I haven't joined them, you big bloody idiot.
我是在努力打败他们
I am trying to beat them.
他们日夜监视着我
And they are watching me day and fucking night.
我还有监...
I've still got the CC...
怎么了
What do you want?
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我只是想为弗林警长祈祷
I just thought I'd say a prayer for DS Flynn.
-你们俩关系一定很好 -我曾是他的警督
- You two must have been close. - I WAS his DI.
我知道你是谁
I know who you are.
每次追捕都是你带队
You led the show on every manhunt.
还有"西卡莫行动"
Operation Sycamore, too.
我自己也在快速通道计划里
I'm on the fast track scheme myself.
-我们通过研究过去的案例 -我以为你是来祈祷的
- We get to study past cases... - I thought you came to pray.
这只是一种说法
It's an expression.
特纳的情况如何
What's the status on Turner?
所有的人员要么在转移中
All assets are either in transit,
要么在有保护的家里或安全屋
with protection at their home address or in safe houses.
这些人员之间的联系是什么
What's the link between the assets?
你并没有参与这次调查
You're not actually on this investigation.
我在支持调查
I'm supporting it.
这是什么意思
What does that mean?
意思是我的朋友中枪了
It means my friend has been shot,
我想确保正义得到伸张
and I want to make sure he gets justice.
你真觉得他们今晚还会再来吗
Do you really think they'll try again tonight?
我们必须假设威胁还没消失
We have to assume an ongoing threat.
但没人能把你弄到这里
But no-one's going to get you here.
橱柜里应该会有白兰地吧
Don't suppose there's a drop of brandy in the cupboard?
爱迪生·姚 格雷戈里·诺克斯 艾萨克·特纳
Edison Yao, Gregory Knox, Isaac Turner -
他们都是中国研究委员会的成员
they're all on the China Research Committee.
嫌犯是想针对整个组织
The suspects are trying to target the entire group.
有可能他们任何一个都可能是下一个受害者
It's possible. You have to assume any one of them could be next.
我们一找到联系 加兰德警司就封锁了那里
As soon as we made the link, DSU Garland put the whole lot under lockdown.
子弹射穿了眼晴
Shot through the eye.
很奇怪
It's weird.
死者站在前门 从窥视孔往里看
The victim was standing at his front door looking through the peephole.
我想也许枪手在门下看到了他的影子
I'm thinking maybe the gunman saw his shadow under the door.
但从姚的监控录像来看 公寓里的灯光
But judging by Yao's CCTV, the light in the apartment
不会投下很明显的阴影
wouldn't have made a very visible shadow.
有多少人员被安置在安全屋
How many assets have been placed in safe houses?
这可能是个陷阱
You could be walking into a trap.
幕后黑手很清楚自己在做什么
Whoever's behind this knows exactly what they're doing.
既然他们能修改闭路电视 也能用它来监控
If they can scrub CCTV, they can monitor it.
他们可能在监视你的一举一动 据我们所知
They're probably watching your every move. For all we know,
他们的目的正是让我们把这些人带去安全屋
the safe houses are exactly where they want us to take these people.
他们如何在安全屋袭击目标啊
How can they target them at a safe house?
那是栋房子 纳迪亚 又不是核掩体
It's a house, Nadia, not a nuclear bunker.
–加兰德在哪里 -和议员在一起
- Where's Garland?  - With the MP.
在哪儿
Where?
你想让我在电话里透露安全屋的位置吗
You want me to disclose the location of a safe house over the phone?
那你在哪里
Well, where are you, then?
全部七名中国研究委员会成员都安全了
We have all seven members of the CRC housed.
每30分钟通知我一次
Update me every 30 minutes.
长官 到底怎么回事
Ma'am. What the hell's going on?
抱歉 长官 但我认为你应该听听凯莉的想法
Sorry, ma'am, but I think you should listen to DCI Carey.
做这件事的人可能是想把所有人
Whoever's doing this may have wanted to drive the assets
转移进警方保护下
into police protection.
-为什么 -把他们变成活靶子
- For what possible reason? - To turn them into sitting ducks.
你认为安全屋的地址已经泄露了
You think the secure locations have been compromised?
考虑到当前风险 我建议立即部署诱饵策略 没错
Given the risk, I'd suggest deploying a decoy strategy immediately, yes.
对不起 有什么问题吗
Sorry, what's the problem?
-没问题 –我听到了诱饵策略
- There's no problem. - I heard "decoy strategy."
我们需要你转移到另―处地点
It would involve moving you to a second property.
-为什么 这有什么问题 -没有
- Why, what's wrong with this one? - Nothing.
这处地点是根据专业操作规程选定的
This property was selected using specialist operation protocols,
每个入口都有经过严格审查的枪械警员把守
with highly vetted firearms officers guarding each access point.
嗯 那你怎么看
Yes. And what do you think?
姚中枪的方式表明 枪手在没有进入房屋的情况下
The manner of Edison Yao's shooting suggests the gunman
就能看到屋内的情况
had eyes inside the property without entering it,
鉴于他安装了家庭监控系统
and given he had installed a home CCTV network...
他的摄像头被黑了
His cameras were hacked.
我很了解这个案子的情况
I'm aware of the working assessment of the case.
-你是说他们现在能看见我们吗 -绝对不会
- You're saying they can see us now? - Absolutely not.
这里的监控摄像头运行在由政府通信总部安装
The security cameras in this property run on an isolated network
并保护的独立网络上
installed and protected by GCHQ.
那就一定不受中国的影响吗
I'm sure that makes them China-proof.
大臣阁下
Minister.
我曾亲自主持过两次皇室婚礼
I have personally led security service protection
和九次国事访问的安保工作
for two royal weddings and nine state visits.
这里的监控 包括整个行动
The surveillance in this property, like the entire operation,
能防中国 防俄罗斯 我敢说火星人也能防
is China-proof, Russia-proof, and, I dare say, Martian-proof.
值得注意的是 唯一证明自己有能力破坏
The only entity that has proved itself capable of compromising
安全屋系统的人 似乎就是凯莉警探本人
the safe house, remarkably, appears to be Detective Carey herself.
但这是严重违规 双方均将
A serious breach for which both parties responsible
受到处分
will be reprimanded.
我向你保证
I assure you...
你在这里很安全 大臣阁下
..you're quite safe here, Minister.
那
It...
那就是别的原因 如果没有生命威胁
It's something else, then. If it's not threat to life, there's a...
-那他们想抓你肯定是有原因的 –瑞秋 我们
- There's a reason they wanted you... - Rachel, let's just...
他们在晚上7点枪杀了姚
Well, they shoot Edison Yao at 7pm...
稍后 我将与负责这份报告的大臣艾萨克·特纳
In a moment, I'll be speaking live to the minister in charge
进行现场对话
of the report, Isaac Turner.
妈的
Oh, fuck!
呃 我 我需要我的手机 政府业务
Er, I... I need my phone. Government business.
-特纳先生 你的手机有安全隐患 -别人的也行
- Mr Turner, your phone is a security risk.  - OK, any phone.
我要给BBC打电话他们还以为我今晚会去
I need to call the BBC. They still think I'm going on tonight.
显然 我的员工中没有人想到 告诉他们一声
Apparently, no-one on my staff thought to...tell them...
我现在请到了内政部安全大臣
Well, I'm now joined by Home Office Security Minister
艾萨克·特纳 晚上好
Isaac Turner. Good evening.
晚上好 哈迪亚
Good evening, Khadija.
赞达面部识别会让英国更安全还是更不安全
Would Xanda Facial Recognition make Britain more safe or less?
政府关于英国边境合同的官方声明
Well, the Government's official announcement regarding
将在几天内发布
the UK borders contract will be made within a matter of days.
恕我直言 大臣阁下 我问的不是这个
With respect, Minister, that's not what I asked.
这是录像 对吗
This is a recording, right?
中国研究委员得出了报告结论
The China Research Committee has concluded its report,
我也已经向内政人臣递交了我的建议
and I've delivered my recommendation to the Home Secretary.
怎 怎么回事
Wh-what... What's happening?
显然 首相有最终决定权
Obviously, the Prime Minister has the final say.
但我相信他会做出正确的决定
But I'm confident he'll make the right decision.
在你看来 什么是正确的决定
And what is the right decision, according to you?
就是这个
This is it.
他们设计你来这里的原因
The reason they wanted you here.
大臣阁下
Minister?
我们承诺过要保护英国边境的安全
Well, we made a promise to keep Britain's borders safe.
最安全的系统就是最准确的系统
The safest system is the most accurate system.
所以 我认为正确的决定是
So, I believe the right decision
将英国边境的合同授予赞达面部识别公司
is to award the UK borders contract to Xanda Facial Recognition.
不久前 有人援引您的话说 把英国的
Not long ago, you were quoted as saying that outsourcing UK
监控业务外包给中国 就像1939年把英国的雷达合同
surveillance to China was like handing a British radar contract
交给德国一样
to Germany in 1939.
我做了调查 没有发现赞达
I've done my research, and I've found no evidence
和中国当局有联系的证据
of a link between Xanda and the Chinese authorities.
作为英国安全大臣
As Britain's Security Minister,
我完全支持中国研究委员会的结论
I fully support the CRC's conclusion.
使用中国人工智能技术不会对我们的安全
The use of Chinese AI technology poses no threat to our safety,
人身安全或我们的生活方式构成威胁
our security, or our way of life.